hello
my name's green and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft today we
will be working mainly on the g team
base
but there's something we need to do
first we need to pick up a report from
our man on the inside
he's been doing his mold duties and we
need to see what he said apparently he's
left me a report and he's told me the
secret location here
and actually while we're here i am
actually due to drop off my next bat oh
wait has that been following me the
whole time
we're here due to drop off all of this
nether quartz because it needs stocking
up again
and i'm going to change the price again
back to diamonds but this time it's
going to be one stack for one diamond
the same price as zedaf is charging in
here so he can't just buy them from the
cart anymore and put them in his shop so
it doesn't really matter where you buy
it from and zf can no longer make money
off of this but i have got more in stock
than zedf but i've also got a bunch of
quartz blocks for myself with that out
of the way
just check nobody's here inside the
furnace there it is mole report number
one let's see what he says the north of
stars base resembles a turtle i feel
this is a tactical maneuver as turtles
have very hard
is this it the main tower okay maybe
he's got some useful information here
the main tower is large and mainly made
of stone it appears to have holes in it
that could be used for arrow shooting
it is also very skinny
a strong breeze from the east could
topple it
it is also empty on the inside well
that's interesting it's empty on the
inside
to the south it appears there is a
weapon highly complex redstone he's told
us
it occasionally makes a moo sound you
may wish to submit this report to g-team
tech for further analysis he's told me
everything i already know
there's
nothing in here
that's new information
ah
mumbo i knew we sent the wrong man in
we definitely sent the wrong man in
what would you do if you were here
right well we better send another report
back okay i'm about to sign and close
new orders so i've written to him
information received usefulness is
questionable your new instructions are
as so create a weapon door or other
redstone contraption for team star he
must make sure that he is in their good
books and they do not suspect that he's
actually a double triple quadruple
something agent
then he needs to rig it after the
ceasefire has ended you must ensure the
blame is put on somebody else also
please report on the quality of the
opposition's facial hair
destroy this message once acquired
g
we need to get this to mumbo i'm going
to destroy the original mole report so
that it's there's no evidence and we
need to get the new orders to him but
i'm not gonna show that on camera i'm
gonna have to let him know some other
way
the orders have been delivered now
and you might be wondering why i've got
so many buckets as well well we'll get
to that a little bit later on but i want
to show you what's been going on in the
base because obviously with the
ceasefire flag coming down fairly soon
we've got a lot to do and recently we've
had the circles added which i think
really tie this whole thing in together
but this isn't a beauty contest is it
this is a full-on fun fight that we're
going to be having so we need some more
offensive and defensive capabilities now
we know that that is a big launcher of
some kind so we've been getting the help
of some cats and we've got some more
work done up here
in this control room we've got several
defenses
and offenses that we can use to our
advantage should they come and because
we know roughly what's coming at us
we've got things that i can use now i
can't actually look we got this anti-gas
thing i don't actually know how these
work i've been told i'm not allowed to
use this one or this one but i can show
you this one
so it opens up and loads of lava comes
out as they approach across the bus so
imagine someone's running across and
then we activate that they could end up
running in lava could make it very
difficult for them now there isn't very
much there might need to little be a
little bit more but there's also these
things super secret weapon of doom do
not test
well that's not tempting
no
oh okay fine
and summon gimme
summon gimme
well who's gimme you may ask
well i'll show you who gimme is
right now and how we got him
he is down there you trapped him nicely
in dirt and
garbage that's all i had i only had
rubbish this was surprisingly easy dude
you told me you were bigging this up
like this is not going to be fun it's
not going to be easy
oh my god i found this this at this
temple
and it's it was luckily so that he was
at the top that that's the whole thing
dude
but yeah my plan is and i don't know if
this is going to work we're going gonna
have to try this out we're gonna put
glass here the guy's two by two i think
so he shouldn't be able to fit through
there
and then now if we go down and put soul
sand underneath him he's gonna start
bouncing and if we just have a minecart
traveling around we should be able to
like nudge him into the minecart easily
are you gonna are you gonna i think we
should rock paper scissors
oh no okay yes three
two
one
okay okay okay okay draw your drawer
okay three
two
one
all right all right
three
two
one
oh yes
the plan with this elder guardian is
we're gonna use him offensively and
defensively so we can protect our vault
with his mining fatigue and we can send
him into hit their base into team star's
base cover it in obsidian and they won't
be able to get to him it'll be super
annoying so we've got big plans for this
guy but we need to keep him well hidden
until the ceasefire ends
all right well if i go down there i'm
going to die so i'm not doing that give
me give me the buckets i'll do it no no
you're gonna die too dude no give me the
buckets give me the buckets i can do it
give me the bug if you go in there
you're dead dude give me the bucket
watch me
you're gonna die dude
watch me are you ready for this
i'm ready
all right we've got charge up here what
what are you doing dude you could just
literally jump in
[Laughter]
i'm in i'm in i got a bubble i got a
bubble yeah you did thanks for water
playing more water i say i need to eat
see successful let's try and put plop a
minecart there you go minecart is a go
no you placed it in the one position
where you can't place it yeah there's
one position i just i i realized
yeah yeah
we actually got him it worked
all right we're officially ready to send
him on into the nether
well i hope so here's the plan i'm gonna
drink this bucket of milk
yeah i'm gonna break this power rail and
real quick place down our regular rail
which should turn this way sending him
down this line onto an activator rail
and hopefully through the portal and i
prepared a pit on the other
this could go horribly wrong with this
okay
he's in yes yeah
he's got three
what are we going to call him
um
james give us with a g with a g
yeah james you mean games swedish things
yeah but it's pronounced
yeah okay maybe jimmy with a swedish g
gimme
yes
okay agree and we have laid down the
track all the way to the hub yeah what a
grind dude this took so long
yeah we've got this guy a personal
roller coaster all the way to a little
hidey hole that i've made
yes all i should need to do and we gotta
we gotta we gotta hope here but if i
break this no no no
yeah
[Music]
i'm going to do it in transit don't
worry i got it oh okay
he's named nice that looks so s that
looks so sick dude
bye
and
in he goes
and please
yes
there he is
sweet uh he's attacking me he's
attacking me he's attacking me the word
okay i need to do one more thing here
i need to
get him on a minecart again yes
and success we have ourselves a little
guardian elder guardian for us to use as
we please
so this is the control room and it
definitely needs spicing up in here
because it's
it's very bare bones i've got to admit
it's super bare bones but most of the
base still is we have more days to come
with all of the
changes we can make as you can see i've
added some glass all over here not
because it looks better but because we
know that they're going to be sending in
some paratroopers and we don't want to
have just this whole
this whole thing open and exposed and
easy to get into
so down here i've added a little
chandelier with some lights but the
biggest thing that we have added to the
base is the underground part so down
here for now we spend hours and hours
excavating this whole area where most of
our main rooms are going to be
now you might be wondering why didn't we
just hide this more carefully
well
we figure that it doesn't really matter
where we hide it it's going to get found
eventually so we might as well just keep
this one open but keep it well defended
and i think this is what i'm going to
time lapse now because there's a lot to
do here and a lot of building
so i think what we're going to do is
we're going to just continue
filling in all of these walls getting
this made the best that we can with the
resources that i have
and this is going to be a giant aquarium
and well we'll get into that now shall
we this time lapse is a couple of
minutes long so i'm going to be
answering some questions from twitter as
i normally do yes i forgot to press f1
we're all used to it by now the first
question is from uk granny gamer now
you've been a youtuber for a few years
how do you keep yourself motivated
that's kind of deep for the start of
this but being a youtuber isn't always
what it's cracked up to be or what it's
made out to be sort of made out to be
this elegant job but the reality is it's
incredibly stressful and because you
work alone most of the time in my case
you have to keep yourself desperately
motivated all the time otherwise you
just stop creating and i do it by making
sure i have my support network of
friends and family and my cats and i
keep myself exercised so that i can keep
putting out great content for everybody
at least i hope so the next question is
from tim how do you come up with the
ideas for the stuff you're going to
build is it planned or do you just make
it up as you go along actually it's a
little bit of both sometimes i'll draw a
picture on ms paint and then i will just
wing it once i actually get into it i'm
going to totally butcher this name but
electric okay
is iskall going to be an architect i
don't know should we invite iskal to be
an architect i might need to
confer with mumbo a bit on that one the
next question by lonely houseboat is who
is the man in the chicken costume
well
we don't know all we know is that he's
gone into hiding and i don't know when
we're going to see him next
and the final question is by carlo what
are the rules for the civil war now this
is a really good question because there
aren't really rules you guys all need to
remember that this whole thing is
genuinely for fun and no other reason so
we're not just gonna go out and grief
each other we're gonna try and create
the funnest battle
that we've ever had and we're gonna make
sure that it's a good barrel of laughs
but yeah we are gonna end up killing
each other in minecraft a few times
a few hours later
and here we are this is currently the
shell for the major underground base now
obviously this is kind of just like a
lobby there's not any rooms in here yet
there's one on the left there but i'm
not allowed to show you that one but
there's one on the right here which is
the armory now there's not actually a
lot you can do with this if the enemy
finds this
whatever it just dispenses all of our
tools on us when we're going on a raid
so it gives us all sorts of cool things
that we'll need to be able to storm them
and it has all of the chests we might
need if we're gonna like if we're gonna
go on the offensive so the idea is we
take all our stuff off we put it in here
and then we go out here to get out of
the base the big problem at the moment
is that there's not really a proper
entrance we just have this and we fall
down at the moment so we're gonna have
to come up with a super secret entrance
and also you didn't see this in the time
lapse but big thank you to iskall and
stress who helped me put this as the
ceiling it is completely black concrete
so it really looks like there's just a
void there which is really cool and i
think the overall effect of this entire
room is really cool now obviously it
could do with a bit of detailing which
i'm thinking could look a little
something like this so i'm gonna dig one
block deeper into this thing
and maybe create sort of a
motherboard style effect
and then add some cyan terracotta just
behind it to give it that bit of depth
and there we go so
something like that but you know all
over the walls to make it seem like
there's some sort of pattern obviously i
could probably do a bit better than this
but honestly i think that this base is
really coming together
very quickly i mean that's why this
episode has taken so long it took hours
to mine all of this out even with a
beacon it took ages it took hours to get
all the resources to make this and then
it took hours to actually build it so i
reckon this entire room took 10 plus
hours on it alone and you know it makes
up a few minutes of the video so i'm
really happy with how this is all worked
out and now this actually gives us the
ability to make all of the rooms that we
want to have for this building just
something like that just all over the
place i think that could look really
cool the overall effect works it kind of
makes it look like it's all kind of
connected it's it's a strange pattern
but i think if it's
put everywhere it will work rather
nicely so i might work on that in the
background but i've definitely had
enough of building this room now this
thing here is kind of like the
centerpiece so this is the aquarium that
i'm hoping that someone else on the team
will take care of for decorating
and i'm hoping that there can be a bunch
of secrets here but this at the moment
is the way out
and also while i was working on this i
noticed something else that we need to
take care of oh there's horses
everywhere we've also added a bunch of
ginger cats of course they have to be
ginger because they're we're part of the
g team so we got a bunch of cats i think
all of these belong to zombie clio you
can see that if they launch some uh
creepers over here it's it's gonna be
chaos so hopefully our little cat
defenders will look after the top of
this base but i
i can't see it ending well if i'm being
honest but let's hope no one's here i
don't see anyone
and
oh cubs here well it doesn't matter the
cub's here because this is actually
something that he made what's this he's
working on
star team
tree of peace
hold on hold on hold on hold on hold on
cub fan
cup fan i just i just saw you build that
he's tr
cub
are you trying are you trying to get are
you trying to make things worse
he claims that he's a neutral shop owner
and then he makes this which i now i
don't know how stupid he thinks we are
but that is going to explode although
admittedly i don't really know how
how does that ex
hmm
is he gonna do one on the other side as
well it'll totally look like he's doing
one on the other side as well i know
your game cub
you can't trick me although i am
actually going to mine this because i
want to know how this blows up
oh
please tell me i didn't lose my stuff oh
my goodness
um why did that instantly explode
i mean i knew it was going to blow up
but i thought it would like you know do
the whole
oh that was a jump scare i'm just glad
that this didn't take everything that i
have from me
oh it's a tnt minecart isn't it so i
don't really know how that works but
it's probably got different physics of
some kind
oh we need to use that
we need to use that somehow
i've got so much junk on me
tree of peace i say
cub fan
i know your game
no harm no foul anyway cub has actually
delivered all of the tnt now that is
really deadly like instant exploding wow
is he making one he's def he's made one
here as well
okay at least that one of them will
definitely probably try as well
oh i was not expecting it to be that
obviously i knew it was going to blow up
but come on i did not expect it to be
that instantaneous
either way cub fan has left the flower
meaning that the tnt is indeed here
i'm pretty sure that's meant to open a
little more than that
something's not right methinks
something's broken back there oh wow and
some cake
ah that makes up for jeez this is what a
hundred stacks of tnt looks like
everybody i don't think i've ever seen
this much tnt in minecraft this is
actually a bit scary how am i gonna
transport all this
uh let's uh
i think i'm gonna put that in an ender
chest because i'm a little bit scared
i'm gonna get a couple of shulker boxes
red ones
cost eight diamonds but i can't be
bothered so he can have a block
okay so we got two red shulker boxes
here
and i think we've oh we're probably
gonna need more than two aren't we 100
stacks
i'm probably gonna need all of these i
think at this point i'm just trading
diamonds with python
because
he recently bought all of the stock in
here so
thanks i think we just exactly traded
actually no i made a bit more profit 38
diamonds not bad
ah better destroy the original mole
report there we go more report one is
gone
all right cleared out some space i seem
to have just been carrying all sorts of
junk around with me most of the time now
we have got a little bit of a problem in
the fact that we need a lot more
interior done to make this all look a
bit more impressive and remember the
more like impressive interior we have
you know uh paintings decorations all
kinds of build the better we are able to
rig it to blow up okay that's the main
thing so like an empty room is really
hard to rig but if it's all full of red
herrings and distractions it's quite
easy
there we go that is what a hundred
stacks looks like
i've got to admit to everybody
the only way
we can keep this safe
because this is gonna be the first thing
that anybody steals from us if they come
here we don't even have a machine that
uses tnt i've just realized
but we've got 100 stacks of it but they
do they use a lot of tnt that launcher
so i need to make sure we keep this safe
and i think the only way to do that
right now
is to put it in an ender chest
okay
i didn't feel too comfortable leaving it
where it was i think that sort of
pattern really works and it'll be so
easy to hide stuff behind these sorts of
things and they might not know so
they'll come into this whole room and
they'll see like you know it's pretty
cool it's got all these decorations but
they won't know where to look straight
away for any hidden secrets half of them
might explode half of them might kill
them you know we've got a lot of options
here and it's going to be a lot of fun
trapping all this but that's going to
definitely have to be in the next
episode i'm going to need some major
redstone help because yeah i can build
the room but i can't trap the room too
well i kind of wish i had the redstone
skills of some of my friends
but it's probably best that i don't
that was really stupid of me
why did i do that
now i've got to say everyone i'm really
impressed with me and the team for
putting together such a large and
complicated base in a week like you've
seen how big my base is and how long
it's taken me over 40 episodes to make
it that big well
this is kind of a similar project in
terms of scale detail and depth but we
just sunk so many hours into making it
that it's come together very quickly and
i don't think we would have ever done
some sort of community project like this
without the civil war happening at all
so this is really fun as a project and
up here i'm thinking because we've got
like two layers right we've got one
layer up here and then we've got one to
hide the redstone and we've got a little
cat here just in case creepies come a
creep in but i'm thinking what if we
open this up maybe maybe i shouldn't
have done that quite as liberally as i
just did what if i think about where i'm
gonna place this
and create like a map room here so the
center
is about
here and if i create a square
i don't know how big the map room is but
i'm basically going to copy and steal
iskall's map room and i'm going to paste
it in here so it's going to take a
little while mimicking all of those maps
but hopefully once it's installed that
will make this room feel a bit well not
more welcoming but a bit more decked out
because at the moment a lot of the rooms
are just empty and a little bit soulless
and that's kind of what i want to fix in
the coming days
we still have a fair few days before the
flag is coming down i know that they're
not finished we're not finished and
there's no point in starting this whole
war until both sides are relatively
ready i don't think we're ever going to
be 100 ready but relatively ready so i
think this the map could be about that
size but i'm gonna have to ask this girl
if i can steal some of his maps for that
and for now why don't i just put some
cake here
so without giving away his location too
much
here we have gimme he's our elder
guardian and in the coming day oh no
please don't attack me in the coming
days we're going to plan a whole thing
now it's not really fair game to make a
railway system in their base right now
but we're gonna send gimme on a little
road trip once that cease-fire flag
comes down we're gonna send him a little
circuit around their base especially
when they're in there so that they get
mining fatigue and imagine they're
trying to build their base trying to
improve their vaults and then all of a
sudden they get mining fatigue and they
can't do anything it's going to be so
annoying for them but anyway i think
that's it for today's video
unfortunately i had to spend a lot of
time on that time lapse but i think it
was totally worth it in the end i've had
to put in extra hours to get the team
ready and this whole base ready in time
for the ceasefire end and it's now time
in the next episode to work on trapping
it the best way i know how without any
redstone
thank you very much for watching today
we have done the mole report on mumbo
although it was very questionable how
good it was
we have done some major work to the base
we have captured ourselves an elder
guardian and all in all we have started
preparing for this war in general i am
extremely sorry that i'm not working on
my personal base but this has just had
me
way more enthusiastic than ever before
it's so nice to be working on a
different project so i am sorry if you
want to see some project on my main base
but hey after this whole civil war oh
after this whole civil war thing is done
then i will be going back there for the
rest of the season so
this won't last forever and i hope
you're enjoying it please let me know
how much you are enjoying the civil war
in the comments down below thanks
everyone for watching and good
bye
oh it's it's in slow motion so i say
good bye